# Dmitrii Maksimov

#### MACHINE LEARNING ENGINEER · DATA SCIENTIST

Erlangen, Germany

📱 +49 15203762106 | 🗷 maksimov.dmitry.m@gmail.com | 28 January 28th, 1998 | 20 Maksimov-Dmitry | 20 Maksim

## **Summary**

Data/Software Engineer at fintech company T.C.R. International and Working Student Data Scientist at GFK. Worked as a Data Scientist at the ratailing company SDVOR in Moscow. 3+ years of diverse data science experience with specialties in market research, data visualization, market optimization and model deployment. 2+ years of diverse data/software engineering experience with specialties in pipelines integration using Airflow, architecture design using AWS, database maintenance and deployment using docker

In addition, while studying at the university and various courses(e.g. MADE from VK), I learned many skills like: **NLP, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Pytorch, Spark, Hadoop, Scala, Recommender Systems, kubernetes, mlflow, algorithms and data structures**.

Love to share knowledge with different communities. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for various tasks and learning new technologies and tools.

## Skills\_

**MLOps** AWS, Docker, GitHub, Retool, Linux, Bash, REST API

Machine Learning, Statistical Data Analysis, Data Visualization, Probability Theory, ETL, Vertica, Search Engine Optimization,

PostgreSQL, Market Research, Parsing, Streamlit

Programming Python, SQL, SAS base, LaTeX
Languages Russian, English, German

## Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

GFK Nuremberg, Germany

DATA SCIENTIST & WORK STUDY

Apr. 2022 - Present

- Creating a tool to compare segmentations and their impact on the market
- Developing a method to detect AoI(areas of interests)
- Investigating cannibalisation effects
- Evaluating competitors algorithm
- Stack: Python, Google Cloud Platform, Streamlit, PostgreSQL

T.C.R. International Cyprus

Data/Software Engineer Sep. 2021 - Present

- Creating and maintaining processes for financial systems(e.g. locates, charging, symbols databased maintaining)
- Optimize airflow dags which allowed to reduce the cost of the astronomer of 70%
- · Stack: Python, AWS, Airflow, PostgreSQL, Retool, REST API, Docker

SDVOR Moscow, Russia

Apr. 2020 - Jan. 2022

• Creating an attribution model in advertising for SDVOR site using Markov chain as a result advertising costs decreased by 5%

- Creating an attribution model in advertising for 3DVOR site using Markov Chain as a result advertising costs of
- · Programming ETL workflows for competitors site's parsing
- · Building service to optimize price for sales using SAS, python, SQL, which increased the profit on some products by 10%
- Accomplishing computer vision model to compare planorgam and realogram via photo in a shop
- Creating telegram-bot as a server for different tasks
- Stack: Python, SAS, Vertica, PostgreSQL, Telegram API

## Education

#### FAU(Friedrich-Alexander-Universität Erlangen-Nürnberg)

Erlangen-Nürnberg, Germany

M.S. IN DATA SCIENCE Oct. 2021 - Present

#### BMSTU(Bauman Moscow State Technical University)

Moscow, Russia

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2020 - Jun. 2021

Finished 1 semester

### **BMSTU(Bauman Moscow State Technical University)**

Moscow, Russia

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2020

• GPA - 4.42, max - 5.0

# **Extracurricular Activity**

MADE at VK

Moscow, Russia

STUDENT

Sep. 2022 - PRESENT

- Gained expertise in different areas of ML (e.g. NLP, DL, CV, MLOps, basic ML, Python, ML in BigData, etc)
- Core member in a project to create a recommendation system for articles' authors

ML at Mail.ru Group

Moscow, Russia

STUDENT

Sep. 2020 - Jan. 2021

• Gained knowledge in basic ML

## **Certificates**

Oct. 2022 Completion of the Deep Learning Exercise, FAU

Mar. 2020 Labeled data learning, Coursera

Mar. 2020 Math and Python for data analysis, Coursera

2019 **C/C++**, Mail.ru Group

## **Honors & Awards**

INTERNATIONAL AWARDS

Jan. 2023 8th Place, Tensor Tournament

Erlangen, Germany

**DOMESTIC AWARDS** 

2021 **1st Place**, SDVOR Hacking Competition

Tyumen, Russia